# Diego Escobedo

Boston, MA | diegoesc@mit.edu | 650-445-9879

Github: github.com/diego-escobedo | Personal Website: diego-escobedo.github.io/diego.github.io/

Trilingual MIT Junior with a unique blend of computer science proficiency and understanding of the economic contexts in which data science can be a driving force. Sound foundation in machine learning, optimization, and algorithms research.

#### Education

#### Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT)

Class of 2022

- Candidate for B.S. in Computer Science & Engineering and B.S. in Mathematical Economics GPA 4.74/5
- Relevant Coursework: Introduction to ML, Design and Analysis of Algorithms, Elements of Software Construction, Optimization Methods: Business Analytics, Math for Computer Science, Probabilistic Systems Analysis, Linear Algebra
- Academic Interests: Combinatorial Optimization, Resource Allocation Problems, Algorithms, Big Data, Public Policy

## Work Experience

Google - STEP Intern

Summer 2020 Mountain View, CA

Google Research

- Created a fantasy basketball engine, where users could build a custom team, insert them into a real NBA season, and use a
- model to predict the outcome of a match between any two teams. Abstracted players into ~30 efficiency and counting stats and integrated their identities into a "bag of players" feature, which allowed for the deep neural network to handle any match between any set of players.
- Model performed at ~78% accuracy, better than most experts and scientific papers. Created using TensorFlow in Python and deployed onto Google App Engine.

### Electronic Arts (EA) – Global Analytics and Insights Intern

Maxis Studios

Summer 2019

Redwood City, CA

Leveraged data from ~1.5M players and developed a RF classifier to optimize targeted advertising and improve key business KPIs. Used data from first few hours of gameplay to predict spend outcome and send offers to ensure indecisive players are brought into the company's pack buyer network. Performed at ~88% accuracy.

#### Stanford School of Medicine - Molecular Imaging Program Intern

Multi-Modality Imaging Lab

**Summer 2017 - Spring 2018** 

Stanford, CA

Invented a 'smart toilet' that analyzes bodily fluids to enable the early detection of diseases such as diabetes, UTIs, and STIs, by analyzing biometric data to create a longitudinal profile of patients' health. Patent pending, filed July 2018.

## Leadership Experience

#### **Amphibious Achievement**

September 2018 – Present

Mentor

September 2018 – Present

Coordinated and developed a dual athletic-academic mentorship program for over 70 high school students with the purpose of expanding their higher education opportunities.

#### Phi Delta Theta - Massachusetts Gamma Chapter

President

September 2018 – Present

May 2020 - Present December 2018 – May 2020

Misc: Recruitment, Judicial, Social, Academics Chair

As President, redesigned the bylaws, improved our safety procedures, and funded a house renovation. Responsible for coordinating over 20 officers' efforts in a variety of areas, including recruitment, social, and academic endeavors.

#### Other

- Programming Languages/Tools: Python, SQL, Tensorflow, Git, Java, JavaScript, HTML, Julia, Google App Engine
- Languages: Fully trilingual in Spanish, English, and Portuguese
- Publications: A mountable toilet system for personalized health monitoring via the analysis of excreta. Nat Biomed Eng (2020). https://doi.org/10.1038/s41551-020-0534-9